## **ABOUT ME**

My name is Kevin Snijders, 26 years old, a hard-working and stress-resistant graduate student as a software engineer at the Hogeschool van Amsterdam. During my study, I enjoyed the knowledge that I gained which was heavily focused on the backend architecture and design. Through experiences such as internships, self study and a parttime job as a Front-end Developer, I found out that I was interested in Front-end as well (maybe even more than Back-end). As a result, I am now focused on finding a job as a Junior Front-end Developer, but maybe in the future, I want to be able to combine them and go for Fullstack.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree, Software engineering. Hogeschool van Amsterdam (Amsterdam)

2014 - 2018.

Applicatioentwikkelaar (MBO 4). Horizon college (Purmerend)

• 2010 - 2014

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Sofa Superstars (Graduate internship)

2017 - 2018

Function: Full-stack Developer

**Description:** For my graduate internship I choice Sofa Superstars again and this time it would be focused on Back-end with a little Front-end. Sofa Superstars wanted to boost the engagement with its users with the functionality to be able to send near-real-time notifications to different (groups of) users. My job was, therefore, to develop a Cross-site messaging system with near-real-time delivery which could be used in their existing products.

#### **Activities:**

- A thesis with research into the various options that could be used for this use case.
- Developing a backend system based on Django, Django Channels and Python.
- Creating API's
- Implementing the use of WebSockets.
- A React library component with Rollup.JS to being able to reuse implement in the various websites.

# Sofa Superstars (Part-time job)

2016 - 2017

Function: Front-end developer

**Description:** After I completed my internship at Sofa Superstars I was offered to work there part-time as Front-end developer for couple days per week. I was responsible for most of the Front-end tasks and a point of contact for a new intern student.

#### **Activities:**

- Developing React components or features.
- Refactoring parts of the older codebase.
- Converting PSD designs (from zeplin.io) to code.
- A point of contact for a Front-end intern.
- Providing support on new and old projects.

# Sofa Superstars (Internship)

2015 - 2016

Function: Web developer

**Description:** In the second year of my study, I opted for a web development internship because I wanted to improve my skills in that area. Since I had only a little experience in this field, I had to start with smaller tasks to become familiar with the technologies that they were using in their codebase. For example, learning how to use CSS preprocessors like Sass and working with a JavaScript framework like React, but also using tools for task managers such as Gulp, and more. At the end of the internship after learning and improving daily, I fully participated in the development team.

#### **Activities:**

- Fixing small bugs.
- Fixing pixels perfect issues.
- Learning Front-end technologies.
- Developing React components or features.
- Converting parts of Vanilla JavaScript to React.
- Working on the responsiveness of various websites.
- The development of FC Groningen Rapport from scratch.

youngbits (Internship)

2013 - 2014

Function: Web developer

**Description:** This was my first Web and Media internship when I was not familiar with the subject at all. During this time I learned the basics of web development, a bit about using photoshop and making a (web) design and editing images.

## **Activities:**

- Converting PSD designs to HTML templates.
- Learning the basics of Photoshop by designing webpages.
- Modifying existing websites (HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS).
- The development of simple (WordPress) websites.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

**Personal website –Front-end Developer (2019 – 2019):** I did not have a personal website to showcase my portfolio yet. This project was split into a Front-end part with the latest technologies used, such as React, WebPack, Flexbox, ESLint and more. The backend is a simple Node Express server with a Postgres database that is used to store projects and the technologies. An API has been created to share this data with the Front-end. The Front-end is deployed by Github Pages and the Back-end with Heroku.

**KLM workshop tool – Co-Developer (2014 – 2015):** The assignment was to create an interactive tool that could be used during workshops. In this case, the client always used printed forms to gather information about a subject. Our solution was to digitalize those forms so that participants could use a computer or mobile instead. To make it useful for the host as well we made sure that there was a host environment. Here it shows the answer given per candidate and indicates which participants were done and which were not done all in real-time. The project was built with Java Spring / Hibernate, AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML & MySQL.

were not done all in real-time. The project was built with Java Spring / Hibernate, AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML & MySQL.
KNOWLEDGE  HTML5, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Jest, Webpack, Gulp, Databases (MySQL en Postgres), Node.js, Python, Django, Java, Git, Github Pages, Heroku, Jira and Scrum.
Docker, Redux (Native) and Vue.
Trustworthy, Flexibility, Perseverance, Teamplayer, Willingness to learn, Patience, and Stress resistant.
Dutch (First language) and English.
DEEEDENCE

#### REFERENCE

Upon request.